I am a palliative care physician
أنا طبيب رعاية تلطيفية
and I would like to talk to you today about health care.
وأود أن أتحدث إليكم اليوم عن الرعاية الصحية.
I'd like to talk to you about the health and care
أود أن أتحدث إليكم عن صحة ورعاية
of the most vulnerable population in our country --
السكان الأكثر ضعفا في بلدنا،
those people dealing with the most complex serious health issues.
أولئك الذين يتعاملون مع القضايا الصحية الأكثر تعقيدا وخطرا.
I'd like to talk to you about economics as well.
أود أن أتحدث إليكم عن الاقتصاد أيضا.
And the intersection of these two should scare the hell out of you --
وتقاطع هذين الاثنين ينبغي أن يُخيفكم بشكل كبير،
it scares the hell out of me.
إنه يخيفني كثيرا.
I'd also like to talk to you about palliative medicine:
كما أود أن أتحدث إليكم عن الرعاية التلطيفية،
a paradigm of care for this population, grounded in what they value.
نموذج رعاية لهذه الفئة من السكان، يرتكز على ما يعتبرونه قيِّما.
Patient-centric care based on their values
رعاية محورها المريض وترتكز على قيمهم
that helps this population live better and longer.
وتساعد هذه الفئة من السكان على عيش أفضل وأطول.
It's a care model that tells the truth
إنه نموذج الرعاية الذي يقول الحقيقة
and engages one-on-one
ويشارك وجها لوجه
and meets people where they're at.
ويلتقي بالأشخاص في مكان تواجدهم.
I'd like to start by telling the story of my very first patient.
أود أن أبدأ برواية قصة لقائي مع أول مريض لي.
It was my first day as a physician,
وكان هذا أول يوم لي كطبيب،
with the long white coat ...
مع معطف أبيض طويل ...
I stumbled into the hospital
تعثرت في المستشفى
and right away there's a gentleman, Harold, 68 years old,
وصادفت فورا رجلا محترما، هارولد، 68 عاما،
came to the emergency department.
أتى إلى قسم الطوارئ.
He had had headaches for about six weeks
عانى من صداع طيلة الأسابيع الست الماضية
that got worse and worse and worse and worse.
ثمّ ازداد سوءًا أكثر فأكثر فأكثر.
Evaluation revealed he had cancer that had spread to his brain.
كشف لنا تقييم أن لديه سرطانا وأنه قد انتشر إلى دماغه.
The attending physician directed me to go share with Harold and his family
أرشدني الطبيب المعالج بأن أشارك مع هارولد وعائلته
the diagnosis, the prognosis and options of care.
التشخيص والتنبؤ وخيارات الرعاية.
Five hours into my new career,
خلال خمس ساعات في مسيرتي الجديدة،
I did the only thing I knew how.
قمت بالشيء الوحيد الذي كنت أعرف طريقة إنجازه.
I walked in,
دخلت،
sat down,
وجلست
took Harold's hand,
وأخذت بيد هارولد
took his wife's hand
وأخذت بيد زوجته
and just breathed.
وتنفست فقط .
He said, "It's not good news is it, sonny?"
قال: " ليس خبرا سارا أليس كذلك، يا بني؟"
I said, "No."
قلت :"لا."
And so we talked and we listened and we shared.
فتحدثنا واستمعنا وتشاركنا.
And after a while I said,
وبعد حين قلت:
"Harold, what is it that has meaning to you?
"هارولد، ما هو الشيء الذي له معنى بالنسبة لك؟
What is it that you hold sacred?"
ما هو الشيء الذي تقدسه ؟"
And he said,
وقال:
"My family."
"عائلتي".
I said, "What do you want to do?"
فقلت له: "ماذا تريد أن تفعل؟"
He slapped me on the knee and said, "I want to go fishing."
ضربني بلطف على الركبة، وقال: "أريد الذهاب الى الصيد."
I said, "That, I know how to do."
فقلت له: "ذلك أمر أعرف القيام به."
Harold went fishing the next day.
ذهب هارولد إلى الصيد في اليوم التالي.
He died a week later.
ثمّ توفي أسبوعا بعد ذلك.
As I've gone through my training in my career,
عند رجوعي إلى تدريبي خلال مسيرتي،
I think back to Harold.
أعود بذاكرتي إلى هارولد.
And I think that this is a conversation
وأعتقد أن هذه المحادثة
that happens far too infrequently.
نادرا ما تحدث.
And it's a conversation that had led us to crisis,
لقد قادتنا هذه المحادثة إلى أزمات،
to the biggest threat to the American way of life today,
إلى أكبر تهديد اليوم لطريقة العيش الأميركية ،
which is health care expenditures.
وهي نفقات الرعاية الصحية.
So what do we know?
لذا ما الذي نعرفه؟
We know that this population, the most ill,
نحن نعلم أن هذه الفئة من السكان، والأكثر مرضا،
takes up 15 percent of the gross domestic product --
تستحوذ على15 في المئة من الناتج المحلي الإجمالي،
nearly 2.3 trillion dollars.
ما يقارب 2.3 تريليون دولار.
So the sickest 15 percent take up 15 percent of the GDP.
إذن ال15 في المئة الأكثر مرضا تستحوذ على 15 في المئة من الناتج المحلي الإجمالي.
If we extrapolate this out over the next two decades
إذا أسقطنا هذا على العقدين القادمين
with the growth of baby boomers,
مع طفرة في عدد المواليد،
at this rate it is 60 percent of the GDP.
فإن النسبة بهذا المعدل هي 60 في المئة من الناتج المحلي الإجمالي.
Sixty percent of the gross domestic product
ستّون في المئة من الناتج المحلي الإجمالي
of the United States of America --
للولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
it has very little to do with health care at that point.
إن الأمر له علاقة ضئيلة بالرعاية الصحية في تلك المرحلة،
It has to do with a gallon of milk,
إن الأمر متعلق بغالون من الحليب،
with college tuition.
برسوم التعليم الجامعي.
It has to do with every thing that we value
إن الأمر متعلق بكل ما له قيمة بالنسبة لنا
and every thing that we know presently.
وكل ما نعرفه في الوقت الحاضر.
It has at stake the free-market economy and capitalism
ما يوجد على المحك هنا هو اقتصاد السوق الحر ورأسمالية
of the United States of America.
الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
Let's forget all the statistics for a minute, forget the numbers.
دعونا ننسى كل الإحصائيات لمدة دقيقة، وننسى الأرقام.
Let's talk about the value we get for all these dollars we spend.
دعونا نتحدث عن القيمة التي نحصل عليها مقابل كل هذه الدولارات التي ننفقها.
Well, the Dartmouth Atlas, about six years ago,
حسنا، قامت دارتموث أطلس، قبل حوالي ست سنوات،
looked at every dollar spent by Medicare --
بالنظر إلى كل دولار ينفق من قبل الرعاية الطبية
generally this population.
- بشكل عام هذه الفئة من السكان -
We found that those patients who have the highest per capita expenditures
وجدنا أن هؤلاء المرضى الذين لديهم أعلى معدل لنفقات الفرد
had the highest suffering, pain, depression.
لديهم أعلى معدل للمعاناة والألم والاكتئاب.
And, more often than not, they die sooner.
وفي أكثر الأحيان، يموتون عاجلا.
How can this be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون الأمر هكذا؟
We live in the United States,
نحن نعيش في الولايات المتحدة،
it has the greatest health care system on the planet.
إنها تتوفر على أكبر نظام للرعاية الصحية على هذا الكوكب.
We spend 10 times more on these patients
نحن ننفق على هؤلاء المرضى 10 مرات أكثر
than the second-leading country in the world.
ممّا تُنفقه ثاني دولة عظمى في العالم
That doesn't make sense.
هذا لا معنى له.
But what we know is,
ولكن ما نعرفه هو،
out of the top 50 countries on the planet
أنه ومن بين أول 50 دولة على هذا الكوكب
with organized health care systems,
ذات أجهزة منظمة للرعاية الصحية ،
we rank 37th.
رتبتنا هي 37.
Former Eastern Bloc countries and sub-Saharan African countries
تحتل دول الكتلة الشرقية السابقة والبلدان الأفريقية الواقعة جنوب الصحراء الكبرى
rank higher than us as far as quality and value.
رتبا أعلى منا في الجودة والقيمة.
Something I experience every day in my practice,
هناك شيء ما أعايشه كل يوم في مهنتي،
and I'm sure, something many of you on your own journeys have experienced:
وأنا متأكد، أن الكثير منكم قد عايشه في مسيرته الخاصة :
more is not more.
أكثر لا يعني المزيد.
Those individuals who had more tests,
أولئك الأفراد الذين لديهم المزيد من الاختبارات،
more bells, more whistles,
المزيد من الفواتير، والمزيد من الصفارات،
it decreases the quality of their life.
فإن هذا يقلل من جودة حياته.
And it shortens it, most often.
ويقصرها، في معظم الأحيان.
So what are we going to do about this?
ما الذي سنقوم به حيال هذا الأمر؟
What are we doing about this?
ما الذي نقوم به حيال هذا الأمر؟
And why is this so?
ولماذا يحدث هذا؟
The grim reality, ladies and gentlemen,
إن الواقع المرير، أيها السيدات والسادة،
is that we, the health care industry -- long white-coat physicians --
هو أننا، في مجال الرعاية الصحية - الأطباء ذوو المعاطف البيضاء الطويلة -
are stealing from you.
نسرق منكم،
Stealing from you the opportunity
نسرق منكم فرصة اختيار الطّريقة
to choose how you want to live your lives
التي تريدون أن تعيشوا بها حياتكم الخاصة
in the context of whatever disease it is.
في سياق نوعية المرض الذي تعانون منه.
We focus on disease and pathology and surgery
نحن نركز على الأمراض وعلم الأمراض والجراحة
and pharmacology.
والصيدلة.
We miss the human being.
لقد افتقدنا الإنسان.
How can we treat this
كيف يمكننا التعامل مع هذا
without understanding this?
دون فهم هذا؟
We do things to this;
نحن نفعل أشياء لهذا الغرض؛
we need to do things for this.
علينا أن نفعل أشياء لأجل هذا الغرض،
The triple aim of healthcare:
الهدف الثلاثي للرعاية الصحية:
one, improve patient experience.
أولا، تحسين تجربة المريض.
Two, improve the population health.
ثانيا، تحسين صحّة السّكان.
Three, decrease per capita expenditure across a continuum.
ثالثا، تقليص إنفاق الفرد عبر سلسلة متّصلة.
Our group, palliative care,
مجموعتنا، الرعاية التلطيفية،
in 2012, working with the sickest of the sick --
في عام 2012، بالعمل مع أكثر المرضى معاناة،
cancer,
السّرطان،
heart disease, lung disease,
أمراض القلب، أمراض الرئة،
renal disease,
أمراض الكلى،
dementia --
والخرف.
how did we improve patient experience?
كيف قمنا بتحسين تجربة المريض؟
"I want to be at home, Doc."
"أريد أن أكون في المنزل، دكتور".
"OK, we'll bring the care to you."
"حسنا، سوف نجلب لك الرعاية ."
Quality of life, enhanced.
نوعية الحياة، معززة.
Think about the human being.
فكر في الكائن البشري.
Two: population health.
ثانيا: صحة السكان.
How did we look at this population differently,
كيف نظرنا إلى هذه الفئة من السكان بشكل مختلف،
and engage with them at a different level, a deeper level,
وتعاملنا معها على مستوى مختلف، على مستوى أكثر عمقا،
and connect to a broader sense of the human condition than my own?
واتصلنا معهم بمعنى أوسع للحالة الإنسانية من حالتنا الخاصة؟
How do we manage this group,
كيف ندير هذه المجموعة،
so that of our outpatient population,
حيث أنّه من بين جميع المرضى الخارجيّين،
94 percent, in 2012, never had to go to the hospital?
94 في المئة منهم عام 2012، لم يكن عليهم الذهاب الى المستشفى؟
Not because they couldn't.
ليس لأنهم لم يستطيعوا ذلك.
But they didn't have to.
ولكن لأنهم لم يكونوا بحاجة إلى ذلك.
We brought the care to them.
لقد جئنا بالرعاية إليهم.
We maintained their value, their quality.
حافظنا على قيمتهم وجودتهم.
Number three: per capita expenditures.
ثالثا: نفقات الفرد.
For this population,
بالنسبة لهذه الفئة من السكان، هذا العدد اليوم 2.3 تريليون دولار
we reduced health care expenditures by nearly 70 percent.
خفضنا نفقات الرعاية الصحية بحوالي 70 في المئة.
They got more of what they wanted based on their values,
لقد حصلوا على أكثر من ما أرادوا بناءً على قيمهم،
lived better and are living longer,
وعاشوا بطريقة أفضل ويعيشون لفترة أطول،
for two-thirds less money.
بأقل بنسبة الثلثين من المال.
While Harold's time was limited,
في حين أن وقت هارولد كان محدودًا،
palliative care's is not.
فإن وقت الرعاية التلطيفية ليس كذلك.
Palliative care is a paradigm from diagnosis through the end of life.
إن الرعاية التلطيفية هي نموذج من التشخيص حتى نهاية الحياة.
The hours,
ساعات
weeks, months, years,
أسابيع، شهور، سنوات،
across a continuum --
عبر سلسلة متصلة،
with treatment, without treatment.
مع العلاج، من دون علاج.
Meet Christine.
قابلوا كريستين.
Stage III cervical cancer,
المرحلة الثالثة من سرطان عنق الرحم،
so, metastatic cancer that started in her cervix,
لذا، فالسرطان المنتشر الذي بدأ في عنق رحمها،
spread throughout her body.
انتشر في جميع أنحاء جسدها.
She's in her 50s and she is living.
إنها في الخمسينات من عمرها ولا تزال على قيد الحياة.
This is not about end of life,
إن هذا ليس عن نهاية الحياة،
this is about life.
بل هو عن الحياة.
This is not just about the elderly,
هذا لا يقتصر فقط على كبار السن،
this is about people.
بل هو عن الناس.
This is Richard.
هذا هو ريتشارد.
End-stage lung disease.
المرحلة النهائية لمرض الرئة.
"Richard, what is it that you hold sacred?"
"ريتشارد، ما هو الشيء الذي تقدسه؟"
"My kids, my wife and my Harley."
"أطفالي وزوجتي ودراجتي النارية".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Alright!
"حسنا!
I can't drive you around on it because I can barely pedal a bicycle,
أنا لا يمكنني أن آخذك في جولة عليها لأنني بالكاد أستطيع قيادة دراجة هوائية،
but let's see what we can do."
ولكن دعنا نرى ما يمكننا القيام به.
Richard came to me,
أتى إلي ريتشارد،
and he was in rough shape.
وكان في حالة يرثى لها.
He had this little voice telling him
كان لديه هذا الصوت الصغير والذي كان يخبره
that maybe his time was weeks to months.
أنه ربما لم يبقى له من الوقت إلا أسابيع أو شهور
And then we just talked.
ثم تحدثنا فقط.
And I listened and tried to hear --
واستمعت وحاولت أن أنصت،
big difference.
فرق كبير.
Use these in proportion to this.
استخدام هذه بما يتناسب مع هذا.
I said, "Alright, let's take it one day at a time,"
قلت: "حسنا، دعنا نأخذ كل يوم على حِدَةٍ"
like we do in every other chapter of our life.
كما نفعل في كل فصل آخر من حياتنا.
And we have met Richard where Richard's at day-to-day.
والتقينا ريتشارد في مكان تواجد ريتشارد يوما بعد يوم.
And it's a phone call or two a week,
وكانت مكالمة هاتفية أو اثنتين في الأسبوع،
but he's thriving in the context of end-stage lung disease.
لكنه نشط للغاية في سياق المرحلة النهائية لمرض الرئة.
Now, palliative medicine is not just for the elderly,
الآن، الطب التلطيفي لا يقتصرعلى كبار السن فقط،
it is not just for the middle-aged.
إنه لا يقتصرعلى من هم في منتصف العمر فقط.
It is for everyone.
بل هو من أجل الجميع.
Meet my friend Jonathan.
قابلوا صديقي جوناثان.
We have the honor and pleasure
يحصل لنا شرف ومتعة
of Jonathan and his father joining us here today.
انضمام جوناثان ووالده إلينا هنا اليوم.
Jonathan is in his 20s, and I met him several years ago.
إن جوناثان في العشرينيات من عمره ، وكنت قد التقيت به منذ عدة سنوات.
He was dealing with metastatic testicular cancer,
كان يعاني من سرطان الخصية المنتشر
spread to his brain.
الممتد إلى دماغه.
He had a stroke,
تعرض لجلطة دماغية،
he had brain surgery,
وخضع لجراحة دماغ،
radiation, chemotherapy.
والإشعاع والعلاج الكيميائي.
Upon meeting him and his family,
قرابة مقابلته هو وأسرته،
he was a couple of weeks away from a bone marrow transplant,
كان على بعد بضعة أسابيع من عملية زرع نخاع العظم،
and in listening and engaging,
وخلال الاستماع والمشاركة،
they said, "Help us understand -- what is cancer?"
قالوا: "ساعدنا لكي نفهم - ما هو السرطان؟ "
How did we get this far
كيف وصلنا إلى هذا الحد
without understanding what we're dealing with?
دون فهم لما نتعامل معه؟
How did we get this far without empowering somebody
كيف وصلنا إلى هذا الحد دون تمكين شخص ما
to know what it is they're dealing with,
لمعرفة ما يتعامل معه،
and then taking the next step and engaging in who they are as human beings
ومن ثم اتخاذ الخطوة التالية وإشراكه باعتباره بشرًا
to know if that is what we should do?
لمعرفة ما إذا كان هذا هو ما يجب علينا فعله؟
Lord knows we can do any kind of thing to you.
إن الله يعرف أنه بإمكاننا أن نفعل لك أي شيء من أي نوع.
But should we?
ولكن هل يجب علينا ذلك؟
And don't take my word for it.
لا تأخذوا بكلامي .
All the evidence that is related to palliative care these days
كل الأدلة التي تتعلق بالرعاية التلطيفية في هذه الأيام
demonstrates with absolute certainty people live better and live longer.
توضح باقناع أن الناس يعيشون بشكل أفضل ويعيشون حياة أطول.
There was a seminal article out of the New England Journal of Medicine
كان هناك مقال مهم في "نيو انغلاند جورنال اوف ميديسين"
in 2010.
في عام 2010.
A study done at Harvard by friends of mine, colleagues.
دراسة أجريت في جامعة هارفارد من قبل أصدقاء لي ، زملاء.
End-stage lung cancer:
مرض الرئة بالمرحلة النهائية:
one group with palliative care,
مجموعة واحدة رفقة الرعاية التلطيفية،
a similar group without.
مجموعة مماثلة دونها.
The group with palliative care reported less pain,
أبلغت المجموعة المرفقة بالرعاية التلطيفية عن ألم أقل،
less depression.
واكتئاب أقل.
They needed fewer hospitalizations.
احتاجوا بشكل أقل إلى علاج في المستشفى.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
وأيها السيدات والسادة،
they lived three to six months longer.
كانوا يعيشون لفترة أطول ما بين ثلاثة إلى ستة أشهر.
If palliative care were a cancer drug,
إذا كانت الرعاية التلطيفية دواء للسرطان،
every cancer doctor on the planet would write a prescription for it.
فإن كل طبيب سرطان على هذا الكوكب سيكتب وصفة طبية له.
Why don't they?
لماذا لا يفعلون ذلك؟
Again, because we goofy, long white-coat physicians
مرة أخرى، لأننا معشر الأطباء الحمقى ذوو المعاطف الطويلة البيضاء
are trained and of the mantra of dealing with this,
قد تم تدريبنا وكتعويذة للتعامل مع هذا،
not with this.
لا مع هذا.
This is a space that we will all come to at some point.
هذا هو الفضاء الذي سنأتي إليه جميعا في مرحلة ما.
But this conversation today is not about dying,
ولكن هذا الحديث اليوم ليس عن الموت،
it is about living.
بل هو عن العيش.
Living based on our values,
العيش بناء على قيمنا،
what we find sacred
ما نجده مقدَّسا
and how we want to write the chapters of our lives,
وكيف نريد كتابة فصول حياتنا،
whether it's the last
سواء أكان الفصل الأخير
or the last five.
أو الخمسة الأخيرة.
What we know,
ما نعرفه،
what we have proven,
ما أثبتناه،
is that this conversation needs to happen today --
هو أن هذا الحديث يجب أن يحدث اليوم،
not next week, not next year.
ليس الأسبوع المقبل، ولا العام المقبل.
What is at stake is our lives today
ما يوجد على المحك هو حياتنا اليوم
and the lives of us as we get older
وحياتنا كلما تقدمنا ​​في السن
and the lives of our children and our grandchildren.
وحياة أطفالنا وأحفادنا.
Not just in that hospital room
ليس فقط في غرفة المستشفى تلك
or on the couch at home,
أو على الأريكة في المنزل،
but everywhere we go and everything we see.
ولكن أينما نذهب وكل ما نراه.
Palliative medicine is the answer to engage with human beings,
الطب التلطيفي هو الحل للتعامل مع البشر،
to change the journey that we will all face,
لتغيير الرحلة التي سنواجهها كلنا،
and change it for the better.
وتغييرها للأفضل.
To my colleagues,
إلى زملائي،
to my patients,
إلى مرضاي،
to my government,
إلى حكومتي،
to all human beings,
إلى جميع البشر،
I ask that we stand and we shout and we demand
أطلب منكم أن نقف ونصرخ ونطالب
the best care possible,
بأفضل رعاية ممكنة،
so that we can live better today
حتى نتمكن من العيش بشكل أفضل اليوم
and ensure a better life tomorrow.
ونضمن حياة أفضل غدا.
We need to shift today
إننا بحاجة إلى تحويل اليوم
so that we can live tomorrow.
حتى نتمكن من العيش غدا.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)